If you're Type B, you need to take care.
If you continue to let it be, it could become a serious,
even life-threatening, situation.
Turn it off!
But this program will reveal the solution in one fell swoop!
This TV is sick!
It's really nothing to be scared about...
How about taking a bath?
Am I gonna die too?
Hah?
What are you talking about? You're only 6 years old!
Sorry!
ashita no koto wa wakannai
We don't know what'll happen tomorrow.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
This feels different from a sacrifice.
nanika ga chigau
Something feels different.
batsu ge-mu ja nante omowanai
I'm not thinking of it as a punishment game.
de nande na no ka wa wakannai
I still don't know why.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
Even though I don't quite feel satisfied with that,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
there's no question that you're important to me now.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
There's nothing in this world that's endless.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
Isn't it painful having to cry?
ai no Sweet Drops, Sweet Drops
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itai ne
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
Don't you want to be kinder?
kimi to iraretara Happy
As long as I'm with you, I'm happy.
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
Don't you think girls can be strong?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
Even though we can be weak sometimes.
bokura no negai wa Happy Happy Happy
Our wish is for happy, happy, happy.
sonna hibi mo Happy
Those days can also be happy.
Just wanna make you happy
Just wanna make you happy.
See you later!
If I don't decide on the next nursery school soon, I'll be in trouble!
I've heard that smart people enter huge companies
that have a day care center on the premises.
But what country are we talking about here?!
Kawachi-san!
Hey!
Kawachi-san, did you get a girlfriend?
What?!
You're going home early all the time these days...
Well, it's not that.
You always used to take the last train, right?
And last year, sales went through the roof because of you,
but at this rate...
Those aren't figures that can be made through just enthusiasm or tenacity.
I was lucky.
After all, my name's Daikichi...
Note: Daikichi means "excellent luck".
Kawachi-san!
Wait!
I'll take that.
Thanks!
You're going to the 4th floor, right?
Yep. You guys doing well, as always?
Not this year.
In fact, this guy was just putting the pressure on me.
Look how my hairline's receding.
After you've achieved results
once, it's tough, huh?
Um, Gotou-san, do you really have a child?
Do you doubt me just because I'm short?
No, you're just so thin, I can't imagine where you stored the baby...
I can't remember anymore, either.
He's two already.
Thanks. Just put them down here.
I'll go with you.
Oh, I can manage.
All right.
See you!
She's as powerful as ever, y'know?
If only Gotou-san had stayed in sales...
She's worked here years longer than me,
but after getting pregnant,
she requested a demotion,
so she could go home at a set time.
Everyone in the company
was talking about her...
How long are you going
to take care of her?!
No time frame has really been agreed on...
Rin-chan, huh?
She's been wetting the bed these days.
And I can tell that it really embarrasses her.
Maybe it's an emotional thing.
But you know, even though children sweat a surprising amount,
they don't as much in the fall and winter, as you'd expect.
That's why the number of times they pee increases.
I always used to be told,
"Pee before going to bed."
Her mother must've had her reasons.
I'd ask her if I could...
But mothers are important, aren't they?
If you're any kind of man, don't give up!
Hang in there!
What'd you play today?
I read picture books... and had a staring contest...
Was it fun?
What's that for?
Rin, I'm gonna make dinner right away.
The moon's deflated, huh?
Mother-Child Health Record Book
Hello?
Well, how's it going?
I'm fine, sure...
I'm not asking about you.
Oh. She's good.
Wait a second, I thought you didn't want to be involved.
You're the one that's taking care of her,
so I can't help it.
I'm gonna try to find some clues about Rin-chan's mom this weekend,
so I'll be out your way.
I see... Then give me a call when you reach the station.
Make sure you dress that girl warmly enough.
Yeah... I'll invite Haruko, too.
It seems she's friendly with her girl.
We passed another car!
Looks like you're having a good time...
Yeah!
We're here.
Welcome back.
Rin-chan, thank you for coming!
Hey!
I'm sorry I don't have anything that would please a small child.
She likes old people stuff anyway. Right?
Are you done already?
Yeah.
Don't come crying to me if you're hungry later.
I'm stuffed...
I'm sorry I couldn't finish.
I'm home!
Sorry I'm late!
That was awful!
What's with that annoying mother and child?!
Big brother!
You seriously took custody of this girl?!
Yeah...
And now the weather.
It's sunny and warm all over the country today.
Temperatures in all regions are about
two degrees higher than average for this time of year,
making for pleasant weather everywhere.
I'm just going to the bathroom.
And now let's look at the forecast for tomorrow.
I need to use the toilet!
I can't go with you sitting there!
Is she always like that?
No...
She's a lot more talkative at home.
She even had fun on the train,
acting like she was on a trip.
But when we got here, the people waiting were the ones who were in a bad mood at the funeral.
What are you accusing us of?!
Dope. If adults are in a bad mood, kids think they're the ones the adults are mad at.
You're right...
It may have been that way for you kids, too.
See?! Insensitive as you are, you were the same way!
And Rin's smarter than you ever were!
Shut up, old man!
Rin-chan, you like cat's cradle, don't you?
Come on, at least answer.
Yeah...
I'll give this one to you.
It's pretty...
Watch Aunty do it first, okay?
"Aunty"? You mean "Grandma," don't you?
You're not old enough to be my grandma!
My! What a good girl!
It's because her standard for old age is way too high!
I'll go first, so watch me!
Huh? Did I do it wrong?
Huh?
This? A 4-step ladder.
My!
A 2-step ladder.
An airplane.
A slide.
A diamond!
That's amazing.
It's easy to do it with this yarn.
Did you make this?
That's right. I knitted it from thin wool.
Doing that makes it the perfect weight,
more than just making loops with woolen yarn.
I know! Since she's good with her hands, I bet she can do beanbags, too!
You hook it around your little finger like this...
L-Like this?
Yeah, that's it!
One, two, buckle my shoe. Three,
four, knock at the door...
What is this?! What the heck is going on here?!
"What is this?!" Isn't this what you wanted?!
Yes?
Who is it?
Maybe Haruko-san.
Rin-chan!
These are pretty! What do you call them?
They're beanbags.
Thanks for coming today.
You do it like this?
Like this?
No problem.
Like this. And you sing
a song as you do it.
I'm really impressed that you can
juggle working and raising a child.
It's hard!
My husband doesn't help
in that regard at all.
Aunty taught me how to do it.
Who's your aunt?
Daikichi's mom.
Are you going to Grandpa's house now?
That's not Aunty, that's Grandma!
Yeah... I thought maybe I could
find a clue to Rin's mother.
Isn't this a pretty string?
That makes sense...
It's really easy to use.
After all, I think a mother is important.
Maybe I can do it good, too...
Go like this, then this...
Huh?
Strange...
Grandpa, you should've at least written a will.
Weren't you worried about Rin?
A modem?
I'm back.
W-What's with that hair?!
She did it like Reina-chan's!
Come to think of it, those clothes too...
These are Kazumi's!
Hah? Kazumi?
Mom! I told you she can't wear old, out-of-style clothes like these!
See! They really do suit her!
Well, I guess they're fine.
Since she has the body type of a modern child, that in itself makes the outfit modern, you know.
This brings back memories.
So how was Grandpa's house?
These were from when you were 4, Kazumi.
I didn't find a single clue.
I see...
Well, even so, we shouldn't impatiently ask Rin-chan about this and that.
You're doing your best.
We may have never told you this...
After you were born, Mom worked.
She hasn't been a housewife the whole time...?
When she was pregnant with Kazumi,
she overdid it and had to be hospitalized for a while.
When she returned to work,
Mom found there wasn't a place for her anymore.
She was terribly depressed.
And Kazumi was so tiny when she was born...
Mom often took off work and came home early for you kids.
And what about Kazumi?
She made raising Kazumi her first priority,
so she ended up as you can see, arrogant and bossy!
How are you on time? Do you want Dad to drop you off?
No, we'll still make it if we walk.
Can we come back again?
She says, "Can we come back again?"
Aunty will be here waiting for you, so come back anytime.
Bye.
W-What are you talking about?!
What's wrong with wanting a grandchild?!
I'd take care of the baby...
I can't work and raise a child at the same time!
For a woman, that's a huge loss!
Besides, I still want to wear a swimsuit and go out drinking...
Hey, Rin, did Grandpa have a computer?
Do you know what a computer is?
Yeah.
Did Grandpa use it?
The maid used it.
He had a maid?
The maid's name was Masako-san.
W-What was she like?
I don't remember that much...
I hate Masako-san...
She hated me and was always angry.
I was scared of her...
That's why I forgot about her.
I see.
It's a little late to be saying this,
but it's tough to work full-time and raise a kid, isn't it?
You've got that right.
There's never a dull moment.
Um, have you ever thought that you were sacrificing yourself
by having a child, Gotou-san?
Are you referring to my change in position?
Sorry. I know this is being rude, but...
Mmm, at the time, I thought that was the best choice,
and it turned out all right, so I have no problem with it.
But even if it was a sacrifice for me,
I wouldn't want to talk about it.
Because words have a strong power, see?
"The spirit of language," is it?
Is that too abstract?
No...
I understand exactly what you mean!
Please tell me more about kids again sometime.
Kawachi-kun, your child is older than mine, isn't she?
I want you to teach me, Senpai!
Rin...
You can wake me up.
But, it's sweat!
Whether it's sweat or whatever, it's fine.
Did you have a bad dream?
What's it like to die?
Daikichi, are you gonna die before me?
Sadness about Grandpa's death...
Anxiety over what would happen if I died...
Fear of her own death...
She isn't able to sort these out one by one, so she's all mixed up.
Rin, everything will be fine until you're a young lady.
When will I be a young lady?
No, everything will be fine until you're a middle-aged lady.
Until then, I am not gonna die!
Count on it!
Okay.
And don't worry about wetting the bed either.
You'll be fine as long as you go to the toilet before bedtime.
The toilet is scary!
I'll go with you at night.
And if you still have an accident after that,
all we have to do is change your pajamas.
Will you be mad?
It's nothing to be mad about, and it's nothing to be laughed at.
Okay.
What'd you want to talk to me about?
I'm sorry this is so sudden, Hidaka-san...
Um... This is out of the blue,
but please transfer me to a section that doesn't require working overtime!
What? Kawachi... Are you serious about this?
Totally serious!
I see. So that's what's new in your life...
Personally, I think it's a real shame...
But I've got a kid, too.
Somehow, I'll try to convince the section chief.
I'm sorry. But I really appreciate your help.
You do know the people under you will make a fuss.
I can't understand it!
Why did it have to be you, Kawachi-san?!
Can't you ask another relative?!
I can't tell him that I insisted on taking her in myself.
And aren't there nursery schools that'll let kids stay until late at night?!
I don't want to work for anyone but you, Kawachi-san!
Certainly, this is sudden...
But higher-ups often transfer people suddenly.
Don't make a fuss!
But... I really am sorry.
Even without me, my section will eventually settle down.
And they should be able to shuffle people around.
If not, there's something wrong with the organization.
But I can't let Rin go on like this!
I don't think...
My line of thinking isn't wrong...
Right?
Maybe...
Did you finish?
You want this much rice?
Yeah, that's perfect!
Admittance Guide
Towel, box lunch, slippers, toothbrush, cup...
With your name on everything!
Futon?!
Oh, that's only for the babies...
All right!
Daikichi, hurry up!
Right now, I couldn't say "This isn't a sacrifice"
without it sounding like a lie...
But I hope I'll be able to think that way in a few years from now.
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
It's a sunny Sunday, early in the afternoon.
kyou wa doko e yukou?
Where should we go today?
kayoi nareta itsumo no michi ga
This path I've grown so used to taking
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
seems to be shining brightly,
terasu atatakai taiyou to
as long as the warm sun is shining
tonari ni kimi ga ireba
and you are here beside me.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
I feel like frolicking about.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe wa dokomademo
Our voices can go anywhere.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
maiagaru kaze ni nori
I'm riding on the rising wind.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe mo tobihaneru
Even our voices will be bouncing.
Rin, you have that same thing on your hand towel and lunch box...
What is it?
Like a dog with huge ears...
It's not a dog!
It's Lop Ear!
Lop...? What's that?
A rabbit!
This isn't a little dog?
It's a rabbit!
Jeez!
Rin, let's go pee.
I already went!
Is that right?
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
Don't you want to be kinder?
Oh, I can't continue it...
Good afternoon, Rin here.
Right now I'm training for the sports meet.
I got much better at dancing!
Next time, or the time after that, I'll show you.
The next story is "Letter".
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
Episode 4
Letter